Hello friends, if you are using a vehicle
and you get its insurance removed, then at some point or the other
you must have needed to get
your vehicle insured,
whether it is your own or from a third
party agency, that is, someone has taken a
photo of your vehicle. In today's video,
we will learn that if you are buying insurance from Policy Bazaar, then
how will you do self-insurance of your vehicle.
What is the importance of insuring this
and what are its benefits, we
will know it all step by step in this video.
Hello friends, my name is
Harvinder Singh and you are watching DSC
Solutions' YouTube channel. Here, every
Sunday at 11:00, we bring a video
for you which will be related to insurance only
and will be very useful for you. So,
if you have not subscribed to the channel yet, then
please subscribe to the channel
and set the notifications to call by pressing the bell icon. So,
without any
delay, let's start the video, friends, first of all, let's
talk about some
precautions that we have to take care of.
Where to park our vehicle  We have to cross and
see what all we have to do, first of all
we have to park our vehicle at such a place
where there is no shadow
of any building, no wire, no
shadow of any tree which is
coming on my front wheel pressure due to which our
video may get rejected, secondly friends, keep
this thing in mind that there
must be four to five feet space around the vehicle in
which you can move around completely and make a video
and the entire vehicle can be captured well,
thirdly your vehicle should be absolutely clean, there should
not be any mud marks, water marks on the vehicle
so that whichever underwriter is checking the video,
he sees carefully
what is the quality of the video, the portion of which is of your
tractor which has 414 condition,
friends keep your
RC and insurance policy with you from all the documents
because they will also be needed in this,
lastly, do not do this inspection
in any garage or any maintenance CR repair
workshop, that
video will get rejected because it is
considered negative that any of the vehicle  If there is a
breakdown and it is not in the right condition, that is why it is being parked
in a garage, then
you have to take care of these things.
First of all,
we need to know that in specific cases, there are two types of cases. The
first, which is most important, is
when our insurance is broken, that is,
in a back-in case, the insurance is
not continuous. After that, to
restart the insurance, the next
insurance company checks the
condition of your vehicle. Suppose the
insurance company will take the responsibility of
repairing your vehicle, then before that, it has the
right to check whether your
vehicle is currently in good condition or not.
Second, from within this, the important thing which
comes when you have a concern is about
transfer by age. Suppose you have
bought an old vehicle and that vehicle is to be transferred in your name
now. The report is also to be transferred in your name
now, then before that, you will have to infect the vehicle. You will have to
inform the insurance company
that the vehicle you have bought, which you
want to insure in your name, is
in absolutely good condition. Now
why is this necessary? Why is infecting the vehicle?
See, there is no inspection in this, Uday, right now,
now the insurance company has
seen the condition of the vehicle and this
video of yours, which is your video infection or
I will save that file in the photos collection,
whenever a
claim comes for your vehicle in the feature, they
give the claim on the basis of
what was the condition of your vehicle at the time when they insured your vehicle, that is, they will
take out the infection report at that time and will
see in it which parts are there which they will
not give you through their before the damage
and
you will get the claim for all the parts which were fine in your inspection report, that is
why infections are important, so
let's start now how to do this market
inspection, let's see
friends, first of all you have to
download the self-destruction app of Policy Bazaar, the
name of the app is PNB Inspector,
you can see it on the screen,
you will download this app from Play Store,
after downloading, click on activate, in this
way the user interface will open, demo
video start infection demo video that
you can watch here, otherwise on our
Videos Now you can make videos by guessing,
click on start the infection,
they have asked for the registered mobile number, so the
mobile number which you are going to enter in the policy
or the one which is already entered, you will
enter that mobile number and the registration
number of the vehicle, below this you are going to inspect this
vehicle, the registration
number of that vehicle, only then it will be in the video with that vehicle
number and mobile number, now they are saying
keep the RC of your vehicle, it is ready and if you have a
previous policy also, then keep the bonnet open
and come and sit on the front driver's seat
and all the window panes should be
closed, the upper side should be open, nothing should be
open, this white is
ready now first start capturing your windshield,
that we have to capture left-to-right, the
entire screen should come in the mobile's view
that
we have captured the entire screen,
after that we will
click done, now record RC and previous year
policy, I have only one more thing
that hey friend, I have recorded C,
if you have it around then take the policy
document for it  We will record in front,
click done. Now start the engine
and record the audio meter.
Now let's start the engine.
Now the engine's kilometer screening has been done.
50,000 314 kilometers is visible in it.
We will click done. If you record the Indian
and chassis number, the engine and
chassis number of your car have a plate, you have to record that.
[Music]
In many cars, it is
also in the front of Maruti cars. In this, it is
also in the engine cabin. In many cars, like we have curd
thick, in this, those who open the driver's side window will be
given such a plate. It will have the
engine and chassis number inside it. We will
click done. It should
not be out of the differential during the entire
recording.
Now we have to cut from front to front from here.
You will
see from above where
you have to take your camera. The engine cabin is done.
Now we will drive from the driver's side. We will take a
side view of this car.
See, the entire car
should come in the camera and the light should not be
complete, there should be no darkness, so that
if there is an impact somewhere, see the amazing performance of my
driving.
If there is any detail, you have to
show it completely, like the
back side of the driver's side
[music]
This is the back side of the vehicle, which
is beneficial, you will show it completely,
this is our logo here, now the driver's side
and front side will come, so
we can show it completely with this,
in what condition is the vehicle, right now it is a
side view,
we have to take a complete 360 ​​degree view of it
[music]
After that we have to
turn it off
and capture its front glass,
after capturing it we have to take it and click on it
and then we have to capture the front door as well,
which is the bonnet of the vehicle,
we have also captured it, then we will finish it, now
coming here the repairing video funny video is being
repaired right now, for uploading,
if you think the video has been made well, then
click on upload and
if you think that it is not made well, there may be
some doubt in it, then
click on upload and we will shoot this video again,
after clicking on plot your
video will be uploaded and your message will come
That your video has been uploaded and
whatever its reaction is or the video is yours,
that message will also come to you,
after that you can make the payment for your policy
and your policy will be generated,
so friends, did you see a simple
video and scalp infection, there are many ways to
take the car for infection,
two of these are important, first of all,
you do not have to pay any charges for
infection, if any other company is closed
then it will charge you conveyance or infection charges, the
second benefit is that you can
shoot according to your schedule, that is,
if someone else comes to infect your car, then
he will tell you his time and
location, then the
infection will be done accordingly and it is possible that
your car is not available at that time, then
your inspection will get delayed, so
why not learn a simple process
and inspect your car yourself, so
friends, I hope
you liked the video, if you
liked the video then please like and share it, do
not forget to subscribe to the channel, see you
More good information and updates in the next video, till then take
care of yourself, stay happy and healthy, thank you to you, there
is a problem.